# **ALEXANDER G. BURNER**

5026 7th Ave NE · Seattle, WA 98105 · (206) 390-2364 · alexburner@gmail.com · alexburner.com/portfolio

#### **OBJECTIVE**

Seeking internship for Summer 2014, with availability for full-time employment beginning Summer 2015

#### **SUMMARY**

Motivated and capable student with eye for detail and comprehensive technological and cultural background. Experienced in balancing user needs with technological constraints. Proficient in translating technobabble into humanspeak. Effective in extracting and transforming abstract desires into strict requirements. Adaptable and voracious in learning current status of complex systems. Eager and ambitious in finding enhancements.

#### **SKILLS**

Systems thinking, Human-Computer Interaction, User Experience, Information Architecture, Branding & Identity, JS, HTML5, CSS3, SQL, PHP, MVC, CodeIgniter, Bootstrap, Wordpress, git/svn, [academic: C/C++, Java, Python,] Graphic editing (Photoshop, Illustrator, equivalents), Photography (film, digital), Video editing (Final Cut, equivalents)

#### **EDUCATION**

## **University of Washington - The Information School**

Jan 2013 - Jun 2015

- Pursuing BS in Informatics with concentration in Human-Computer Interaction
- 3.6 Cumulative GPA

## New York University - Tisch School of the Arts

Sep 2007 - Jun 2009

- Studied Computer Science, Psychology, Film & Television
- 3.4 Cumulative GPA

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### Informatics 101 Teaching Assistant @ University of Washington

Sep 2013 - Present

- Planning and guiding discussions on topics for Social Networking Technologies
- Leading quiz section activities for 25 students in two 2-hour classes each week

## User Researcher, SharePoint Designer & Developer @ Quorum Review

Jul 2013 - Aug 2013

- Conducted research and interviews into current and future tool usage patterns
- Created custom SP2010 Master Pages for internal department and team sites

### Information Architecture & User Experience Designer @ University of Washington

Apr 2013 - Sep 2013

- · Worked with Informatics professor Bob Boiko and team of four graduate students
- Helped redesign online gamified learning system (gClass) used for teaching INFO101
- Built prototypes & new front-end interface using the Twitter Bootstrap framework

## Mobile Application & Back End Developer @ ground(ctrl)

Sep 2010 - Dec 2012

- · Built company's first mobile application using JavaScript in the Titanium framework
- Built ticket scanning app and managed staff for entry gate at FFFFest 2011 & 2012
- · Built backend, desktop site, mobile site, and JSON API for room reservation system
- · Led two talks on basic and advanced JS for ground(ctrl) / BKWLD / Elastic office

### Web Design & Development Intern @ BKWLD

May 2010 - Aug 2010

- Worked on icon design, site design, front end & Wordpress development
- Completed design & development of new website for Elastic Suite

### Company Founder & Creative Director @ Vida Pura Clothing

Apr 2009 - Sep 2010

- Inspired, cofounded, and operated apparel design company with five associates
- Managed identity, business strategy, product design, site design, marketing